FAHAD ALMATRAFI

PROFILE

A Product Development Engineer with robust problemsolving skills and proven experience in ECP Projects and an IoT Master's student leading the digital transformation. Providing support in engineering aspects, including Schematics, Specifications, and shifting the manufacturing process to be automated (smarter).

CONTACT

CELL

+966565152245

EMAIL:

fahad.almatrafi@outlook.sa

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/almatrafi/

EXPERIENCE

PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Alismail Industrial Co.

(Dec, 2020 - Present)

- Modeling, Testing, and commissioning the new products.
- R&D, Digital Transformation leader.

INSTRUMENTATION & CONTROL ENGINEER

Al Zamil Heavy Industries Ltd.

(Feb, 2018 - Dec, 2020)

- Prepares specifications, datasheets, BOM, and MTO to purchase E&I materials.
- Designs 3D Model using SolidWorks and implements Instrument layouts in AutoCAD.
- Applies tests to various sensors and instruments and checks if they are installed properly.

EDUCATION

KING FAHD UNIVERSITY OF PETROLEUM & MINERALS

Master's Degree in Internet of Things (IoT) & Embedded Systems.

Bachelor's Degree in Applied Electrical Engineering.

(Aug, 2020 - Present) (Jun, 2017 - Graduation)

PROJECTS

• Tamimi Production line - **NEOM**

(2020 - Present)

• Onshore maintain Potential Projects - Gas Modular Packages.

(2018 - 2020)

• Oil Well Tie-Ins Modular Skids - **Haradh & Khurais.**

(2018 - 2019)

• A Network of Wireless Sensors for Agricultural Systems.

(2017)

QUALIFICATIONS

2020 Project Management Professional (PMP)® - By PMI

2020 Leading Creative Transformation in Critical Times Program - By Standford

2019 Fundamentals of Engineering (FE) - By NCEES

2019 IE0712: HART Signals & Communication Protocols - By Haward Technology

2019 IE0030: Process Control & Instrumentation - By Haward Technology

2018 Saudi Council of Engineers Membership

REFERENCES

ABDELLAH ESSENDOUBI

Head of Services & Technical Support, **Siemens Cell**: +966560670531

ASIF IQBAL

Sr. I&C Engineer, **TechnipFMC Cell**: +966564747258